joined by my guest Joe Laurier in
Alexandria he's the editor-in-chief of
consortiumnews.com in Washington we have
John kiriaku he is a former CIA officer
and in Paris we crossed through Jean
Brook Mall he is a political commentator
all right gentlemen crosstalk rules in
effect that means you can jump at any
time he won and I always appreciate it
I'll go to Joe first and Alexandria
there's not much debate in Western media
in Western in the public sphere in
general about the conflict in Ukraine
which is a real pity because at the end
of the day it is at the expense of the
ukrainians actually but because there is
no trust left we have admissions from
Merkel perochenko and Olan that they
never dealt in good faith with the
Russians and I'm obviously making
reference to the minska process so
negotiations at this point are not
really in the cards and I really don't
see how an informative sense
negotiations we played out this is going
to be done unilaterally one way or
another Joe
yeah unfortunately you're probably right
let's establish that this war should
never have happened because as you said
they wouldn't they were not serious
about the Minsk Accords they were
deceiving Russia to set up uh to train
NATO to train Ukraine for the war that
they wanted that they needed it started
in 2014 with a coup you nobody in the
west knows that very few people there's
no debate there's no discussion there's
no historical context there's no
understanding of what Minsk is there's
no understanding that NATO uh was all
and the US were offered treaty proposals
in December of 2021 by Russia to create
a security architecture that would
include Russia's security interests all
of that was ignored by the West because
they wanted this war and they got it and
they have no intention you're absolutely
right of negotiating this they
are admitting that we're that Russia is
winning the war that Ukraine is losing
even though it's very difficult to know
exactly what's going on on the ground by
the very fact that they want to send
more more RMS including these German
tanks which is the big issue being
discussed so uh I I'm afraid that there
are various scenarios and we don't
really know of course it's impossible to
know when and how this war will end but
the scenarios would be uh the
destruction of the Ukrainian military
um the the
um Russia could seize all of it to start
Russian lands that were in Ukraine they
could have to take Kiev perhaps in order
to finish denotification although I
don't see battling for Kiev uh in the
streets of Kiev to take over the capital
but some engineering of a coup d'etat
may be possible that may end the war uh
ultimately the West wants to keep
bleeding Russia so they can get back to
their ultimate aim which was to
overthrow the Russian government weaken
it with the economic war with the saint
with the information War but the proxy
where all of which are failing I must
say okay John let me go to John in
Washington you know one of the
discursively if you look at how this
narrative has been constructed and Joe
did a wonderful job of introducing it
here the problem with negotiations as
people call it in the west is that
towards what end see I would like to see
peace how do we achieve peace but the
problem is NATO Washington London
Kevin Warsaw because those are the major
Capitals in this they want Victory now
see Victory and peace you know they're
two very different things and if you
want Victory well you're you're playing
you're all you're playing with the with
the ultimate uh uh weapon that could
possibly used in a conflict but if you
want peace that's a very different story
but that's that's not a track they want
to take John
oh I think I think that's exactly right
Peter uh and you know the the American
government has has not prepared the
American people or the American Congress
for peace they've only talked about
Victory and you're right they're two
very vastly different things uh you know
here in the in the U.S in the mainstream
media we see only news about how well
Ukraine is doing we see reports with
headlines saying Russia is losing uh
that's a disservice to both the American
people and to the Ukrainian people
nobody's prepared for either a long-term
uh uh battle or for peace which as you
note correctly is is very very different
from uh from Victory Sean you know
because of the way the narrative is
constructed here Europe is taking the
brunt of this at least economically we
may even see social and political unrest
as a result here because you have
characters like the head of NATO
steltenberg if if Ukraine is defeated
then the West is defeated but I thought
the West wasn't involved in this war
they can't even keep their narrative
straight here and and and and what it
does is is that I can guarantee you am I
only expressing my personal opinion
Russia will not lose this conflict under
no circumstances under no conditions it
will not lose now what losing and
winning can be up you know it's in the
eyes of the beholder let's put it that
way but from the Russian perspective
they're not going to lose this I don't
think Europe was prepared for that the
decision makers for the the preparing
for this war they weren't prepared for
that Russia was supposed to Buckle in a
matter of days the ruble was going to go
to trash and it would be all over but
it's it hasn't and it won't happen Jean
go ahead in Paris
no I'm quite convinced that Russia will
not lose but of course Ukraine is losing
but it's not collapsing yet at least you
see the the fog light move but not not
very fast I mean it's not like the
German line in 1918 it's still more like
the trenches were so I don't know what's
going to happen I mean the westport's
more more and more weapons there I know
what's going to happen but I'm worried
about the intensification of the
conflict now Estonia is speaking of
blocking the Gulf of Finland if they do
that it's an act of War yeah but of
course if Russians react to that they
would easily overrun Estonia that's not
the problem but then it will be another
unprovoked aggression against a NATO
member Article 5 blah blah blah I don't
know what they're going to do and I'm
also interested in the internal
repression especially in France because
you may know or not know but now they
have totally canceled banned active
hands they have cut their they are
source of funding I mean the banks
cannot pay them and get money anymore so
the the banks cannot pay the company
their workers so you have a hundred plus
uh journalists all on the door at the
same time and there is a campaign
against them some people say they should
be vidify they've been working for the
enemy and so on so forth I mean the
attack on rft France are just
unbelievable unbelievable
it's not unbelievable because they don't
believe in free speech anymore that is
something they don't care about let's
say that's the least you can say but the
grade 68 newspaper Liberation which
still has surgery an old 68 they're
coming back to Hype for them of course
violently anti-russian editorials I mean
this newspaper was the first the most
vicious against RT and wanting to bang
RT so it's really you know in 60 they
say is forbidden to forbid but now of
course it's compulsory to forbid it is
amazing how the the change of the
situation and then and then of course
yeah I mean RT depending effective for
me is a major step and of course
not as influential as he used to be now
he says there should be of course
tribunal after the war tribunal of
course for the Russian leadership but
also for the collaborators and their
includes okay John you're making my
point here let me go back to Joe here a
tribunals all of these things here I
mean there's there's no pretense of
trying to find a solution to this
conflict here there is action there is
one though go back to December 17 2021
that's what Russia wanted it was made
public and it was brushed off those
still those demands are still there and
that's your starting point if you want
to have negotiations but I think we're
going to get the same exact response as
we did
um this time as we did then Joe
in April there was an opportunity there
was an opportunity for a negotiation
right then and Ukraine would have come
out in a lot better shape of course they
would have had to agree that Crimea and
the Don bass were part of Russia and not
joined NATO but of course the United
States and Britain but Boris Johnson in
the Forefront prevented that negotiation
and they will continue to prevent that
if bakamut falls or when it falls that
could be an opportunity then to enter a
negotiation because that is a very
symbolic battle going on right now but I
don't think that's going to happen
because the West wants this war to
continue with the grave danger that it
could escalate to the S the ultimate
conflict and that could be the way the
war ends we're all dead and this is what
the West is playing with fire right now
they will not accept that
um ultimately they will have to agree to
those treaties or some form of that that
they will have to accommodate Russia's
security interests like the osce said
like the uh the Helsinki Accords this is
something that that even macron and
Schultz at least that early on in the
conflict were making some noises about
it until America told them to shut up
basically so I that is the only way to
do it is to get a negotiation I don't
know whether Russia is interested at
this point in a negotiation we don't
know exactly what they're well but Joe I
think I can answer that a little bit at
least for my observation let me go to
John here well why would the Russians go
into negotiations with anybody in the
west they've been lied to left right and
Center for years why would you even
contemplate talking to these people no
what's going to happen is political
facts on the ground will be made John go
ahead in Washington yeah exactly you're
exactly right Peter you can't you can't
trust anything that the West says
because everything has been a lie you
know we say this here all the time uh
the Russians have several different
times just in the most recent history uh
trusted the West to be honest in their
uh negotiating points and they've never
been honest you know we hear a lot too
Peter here in the United States about
the Russians being willing to fight to
the last Ukrainian well I would say that
the truth is that it's it's the
Americans and NATO that are willing to
fight to the last Ukrainian we hear in
the news every day hear about tanks
right all the news over the weekend was
about tanks tanks tanks tanks aren't
going to change the course of this war
the ukrainians can't win this over the
long term the only way that they could
is with direct NATO uh intervention and
that just simply won't happen in the end
uh we're gonna see the destruction of
Ukraine we're going to see the
destruction of the Ukrainian government
and we're going to see the the movement
of the Ukrainian people out of the
country unless they agree to sit down
with the Russians just as the Russians
ask many many months ago and negotiate a
deal yeah well you know all I can say
about the ridiculous tan conversation
they will they all melt the same way
gentlemen they all melt the same way all
right gentlemen I'm going to jump in
here we're going to go to a hard break
and after that hard break we'll continue
our discussion on the end game okay
let's go back to Jean in Paris you know
if we look at all of the recent
controversies and we can go back to
Russia gate and we can go back to
um perceptions of the 2020 election in
the United States we and all the things
floating around the Biden Administration
right now
and then of course we have Ukraine and
you know if they all have one thing in
common bad and flawed narratives create
bad outcomes bad policy outcomes and
we're talking about in this program
possible end game negotiations but if I
go to our guest in Paris well any
negotiations with the Russians is Munich
it's Munich every day it's Munich okay
how do you get out of that cul-de-sac
because you know they it's giving moral
justification geopolitics is not about
morality it's not about values it's
about power okay but the West will
always commingle all these other
ridiculous things and never really get
to the heart of the matter as I said in
the beginning of the program if you want
peace then work through that prism they
refuse to do it because every day is
Munich go ahead John in Paris yeah yeah
it's funny that in Germany for example
the IFD is warning against sending
thanks to Ukraine saying that last time
they did it namely in 41 45 he didn't
end up very well and in France the
people who call themselves
anti-fashionists say no no because I
mean no no because of the German past
they must send the tanks because the new
Hitler is of course Putin I mean it's
completely ridiculous you know a long
time ago the next communist told me that
the problem with censorship if you
censor all your this all your opponents
then when you make a mistake there is
nobody to tell you and that's exactly
what the West is doing now by basically
shutting down all the voices and I gave
the example of RT ft was after the whole
domain I I've known many journalism
they just wanted to get give a job while
giving alternative information like
people do on the on smaller you know
websites but then of course those people
have to beg for money and they don't get
paid and uh when you work for RT you
could do the same work by you were being
paid that's the difference but these
people are not putting up
all those I've known and have known
several of them they were not like that
well I mean when the problem I mean it's
not about being pro-russia anti-russia
pro why don't you just have a debate
about the issues that's all I try to do
on this program okay you can dissent all
you want you can tell me anything you
want we barring swearing at me and I
don't really care because it's your
opinion let me go to Joe Joe in
Washington Alexandria excuse me
um you know Joseph Burrell the vaunted
uh EU
foreign policy uh Chief um he said
something very curious the last few days
he said West has to support Ukraine and
but respect Russia because Russia
defeated Napoleon and Hitler so that's
why the Western support Ukraine I mean
the the the lack of logic and clear
thinking from these people is really
astounding I mean their foreign policy
Chief doesn't know his history very well
that makes him you know a person to to
talk about in entire blocks security
future with its neighbor it's
extraordinary the lack of Merit and
competence these people have Joe
yeah well sometimes these people that
are held up in the media as being the
great leaders are not very smart as you
just pointed out but the ones who are
smart know exactly what they're doing
here and I think there are smart people
yeah in the U.S leadership who know
exactly what they're trying to do this
is for the U.S the opportunity they've
wanted ever since uh Putin came to power
and Yeltsin was gone and they lost
control of Russian uh Society finances
resources this is what they want to get
back again but we have to understand
that the the leaders themselves may be
self-deluded they they have created an
incredible psyop and they may be victims
of their own psyop and that's what is so
frightening about this that the
escalatory nature of the U.S position at
the beginning it was Biden who said
clearly uh we're not going to get NATO
involved we're going to stop you won't
be able to attack Crimea we're not going
to send weapons that could reach into
Russia this keeps changing and this is
what's so worrying right now so that the
ultimate scenario could happen would be
the the ultimate end game which is the
end of the world and I don't know
whether this understanding isn't a
person like analina bareback the foreign
minister of Germany for example or even
Joe Biden anymore I wonder if they would
know the fire that they're playing with
here and the only negotiation right now
could stop this otherwise this could go
on for years and if it goes on for years
and it could lead as I say to the
absolute greatest nightmare of History
you know I saw John I saw John nodding
his head there go ahead tell me why
you're naughty when Joe was speaking go
ahead
well I I think Joe's right and you know
I think that the West should pay very
close attention to a tweet from former
prime minister uh Medvedev on Friday and
and a statement uh just yesterday or day
before yesterday by the chairman of the
Duma Russia will not lose this fight
period this is an enormous country it's
a nuclear power Ukraine is an
existential threat we hear a lot of
comparisons here in the United States to
the U.S fights in Iraq and Afghanistan
there's nothing similar there's nothing
comparable between you the U.S and
Afghanistan and Iraq and Russia and
Ukraine and it's because Ukraine is
directly on Russia's border it's an
existential threat and because it's an
existential threat Russia cannot and
will not lose this fight I think that's
something that the West just simply
doesn't understand and appreciate yeah
because they're they're they're they're
they're
blinded by their own ideology about
their own um moral virtue it's really
bizarre when they're putting the entire
fate of humanity uh uh uh based on their
self-perception of their virtue versus
to the other meaning the Russia or I
mean you could go back to Burrell the
garden and every in the jungle okay
that's how these people think very
neocolonial in a way Sean you know we're
talking uh unfortunately in some sense
apocalyptically here but before we get
that
the U.S pays almost nothing it's not
losing troops it's making a armed sales
left right and center and Europe is
paying the price on almost every single
way I mean we talk about and and I I'm I
it's true truly saddens me the suffering
of Ukrainian people because this
conflict should have been avoided it was
avoidable
um but I I but I love Europe just as
much and I just see Europe paying the
cost here what you know the the Germans
the French now we're announcing 40
percent increase in defense spending
yeah well you had your welfare state
because you didn't have to spend so much
on the military okay that's all going to
go away your civil liberties are under
challenge you've been talking about RT
France here I mean you know for all
Europe supportive of Ukraine what to get
for it what's it get
nothing but the intellectual and the
journalistic class has been totally
bought by the United States that what
the girl was saying you know the goal
said that the way the Americans do they
give you a pack of uh whiskey bottles or
they send you a seminar in the United
States or a dinner in Paris or something
like that and that's the way the
corruption goes and the whole class has
been corrupted beyond belief I am up to
the debuffle to see how a case of impair
this message used to say these people
have become I mean they're completely
case of the United States and it's all
because its freedom is democracy and so
on they don't inquire about any lack of
democracy of freedom in the United
States and they they are and I I I truly
believe that politicians like shows and
maybe
are not as Extreme as they seem and
they're not as Extreme as the media but
they are constantly under pressure from
the media or on the genes in Germany the
greens are just unbelievable they are
the most walleye party that you've ever
seen in government well Sean you know I
don't want to ask anybody their age on
this program but I do remember when the
greens were very very different in the
1980s okay we'll have to do a special
program on that because I don't know
what the hell happened to those people
here but let me let me go to to Joe Jean
brought up something I think that's
really important
um Sergeant Schultz as I refer to him on
this program and macron they have it's
very interesting I'm glad John brought
this up because you know if you listen
to them closely like on even days
opposed to odd days they talk about
after the conflict what has to happen
and they get shut down immediate or in
the same speech you'll see but we're 100
behind Ukraine you know whatever it
takes but both of them are actually
thinking about after the conflict which
is very interesting to me and they have
their eye on Washington at the same time
Joe go ahead
well they these are the two who could
have provided the Vogue leadership that
was needed to avoid this conflict and
instead they uh as Jean pointed out they
get brow beaten they get bright I'm not
saying McConnell and and uh Schultz were
bride but that is the European political
class this was Europe's chance also to
be independent of both Russia and China
and the United States to stand on its
own and they blew it as well they have
become more and more of a vassal of the
United States than ever before and this
is one of the great tragedies that we've
seen on falling up to the point where
their own interests the interest of
their own people they have to win
elections are being hurt so badly it
started way back in 2014 when Germany
was forced by the U.S to put sanctions
on on Russia back then and the German
businessmen went crazy they didn't want
it then and Merkel went along and did it
anyway because the Americans wanted to
and they were listening to her telephone
so she probably knew that so I mean it
is a tragedy all across the board here
and unfortunately uh and this
conversation hasn't changed my mind one
bit I don't see any way out of this I
only see things getting much more
frightening and more dangerous every day
this conflict goes on I I agree with you
and and and John you know you know being
an American Living in America the the
have we reached a peak uh zielinski yet
because I mean it's it's truly
extraordinary I've never we thought you
know we thought the you know the drive
to the Iraq War was like you know the
the greatest propaganda Gambit of all
time this has to take the cake I mean
it's extraordinary when I talk to people
the lack of knowledge we have you know
when the catastrophe hits no one in
America or virtually no one in America
is going to know why go ahead John
Peter you can buy zelinski action
figures in stores now that's how we've
reached the point of of ridiculousness
that you can buy a zelinski action
figure to have as a souvenir
um you know one of the things that has
surprised me from the very beginning of
this conflict is that so few Americans
recognized what was behind it the United
States cannot maintain its its
International
hegemony when there's a strong Russia
and a strong China it would have to
destroy one in order to focus on the
other and I think that's what we're
seeing here this is an attempt by the
United States and its NATO allies
to destroy Russia or to bog Russia down
over the long term in a war that was
slowly bleeded so that the United States
can then focus on uh confronting China
that's why we saw uh Nancy Pelosi go to
Taiwan with no complaints well and John
and John and
please
his way here gentlemen that's all all
the time we have here but I'll make my
prediction at the very end being the
host of the program the end is the end
of NATO and that'll be a good thing okay
I want to thank my guests in Washington
Alexandria and in Paris